<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Fahim Dalvi</title>
    <link>https://fdalvi.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Fahim Dalvi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Jun 2021 12:00:00 +0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://fdalvi.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://fdalvi.github.io/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fdalvi.github.io/projects/</guid>
      <description>NeuroX: Explainable AI
Interpretation and Explainability for Deep NLP models. Lots of analysis of Foundational language models and Machine Translation models. Research assets and toolkits for easy interpretation at the neuron-level in Deep NLP models.
Python Flask PyTorch Transformers React Live Speech Translation
Bilingual Arabic and English transcription and translation platform with a robust backend enabling live broadcastable sessions
React NodeJS MongoDB Nginx Puppeteer Artillery.io Shaheen: Machine Translation API</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>https://fdalvi.github.io/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fdalvi.github.io/research/</guid>
      <description>2024 LLMeBench: A Flexible Framework for Accelerating LLMs Benchmarking Fahim Dalvi, Maram Hasanain, Sabri Boughorbel, Basel Mousi, Samir Abdaljalil, Nizi Nazar, Ahmed Abdelali, Shammur Absar Chowdhury, Hamdy Mubarak, Ahmed Ali, Majd Hawasly, Nadir Durrani, Firoj Alam The 18th Conference of the European Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics The recent development and success of Large Language Models (LLMs) necessitate an evaluation of their performance across diverse NLP tasks in different languages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching</title>
      <link>https://fdalvi.github.io/teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fdalvi.github.io/teaching/</guid>
      <description>Neural Networks for NLP Guest Lecturer Carnegie Mellon University Qatar, 2022 Two-part guest lectures for the 67-212 course taught at Carnegie Mellon From Theory to Practice: Deep Learning for NLP Co-Lecturer Universität Duisburg-Essen, 2018 A 5-day lecture series covering the basics of machine learning, neural networks and deep neural networks. We look at several deep neural network architectures from the perspective of applying them to various classification tasks, such as sequence prediction and generation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Consuming Paginated API&#39;s in Javascript</title>
      <link>https://fdalvi.github.io/blog/2021-06-11-consume-paginated-apis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jun 2021 12:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fdalvi.github.io/blog/2021-06-11-consume-paginated-apis/</guid>
      <description>Several providers adopt a notion of pagination in their API&amp;rsquo;s when the number of results from a query is large. This is common to see when the API provides a list of things, like users, billing statements, posts and so on.
A pattern that is adopted by several providers works as follows:
Developer makes a request to provider (e.g. for the billing statements) The API returns a &amp;ldquo;page&amp;rdquo; with say 10 statements, and a link to the next page Developer makes a request to the provided link The API returns another &amp;ldquo;page&amp;rdquo; with statements, and no link Seeing no link, the developer now knows that all the required entries have been fetched The number of pages can be dynamic, so the developer needs to keep following the links until they exist if they want to fetch all the results.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID19 Vaccine Registration Guide for Qatar</title>
      <link>https://fdalvi.github.io/blog/2021-03-29-covid-vaccine-registration-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Mar 2021 12:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fdalvi.github.io/blog/2021-03-29-covid-vaccine-registration-guide/</guid>
      <description>COVID-19 vaccine registration guide in English, Urdu, Tamil, Sinhala and Hindi. More languages coming soon!
How can I register for the COVID-19 vaccine in Qatar? (English)
میں قطر میں کووڈ ۱۹ ویکسین کیلیے کیسے رجسٹر کر سکتا ہوں؟ (Urdu)
நான் எப்படி கத்தாரில் COVID 19 தடுப்பூசி பதிவு செய்யலாம்? (Tamil)
මම කොහොමද කටාර් COVID-19 එන්නත් සඳහා ලියාපදිංචි විය හැකිය? (Sinhala)
कतर में COVID-19 के टीके के लिए पंजीकरण कैसे कर सकते हैं?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating Video Screencaps using FFMPEG and ImageMagick</title>
      <link>https://fdalvi.github.io/blog/2018-09-01-creating-video-screencaps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 12:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fdalvi.github.io/blog/2018-09-01-creating-video-screencaps/</guid>
      <description>I recently wanted to create screencaps for a large set of videos of various lengths and resolutions - basically screenshot each video 5 times, and then combine these 5 screencaps all into one nice image per video, with all of the images being of consistent size.
Sample render from a seaplane ride over Vancouver
There are a bunch of tools available online that I can either install locally, or upload my video files to get similar results - but given that this was easily achievable using simple tools like ffmpeg and imagemagick, I decided to whip up a quick script to accomplish this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing GroupMe Archiver</title>
      <link>https://fdalvi.github.io/blog/2018-08-20-introducing-groupme-archiver/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 16:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fdalvi.github.io/blog/2018-08-20-introducing-groupme-archiver/</guid>
      <description>I was recently looking into various ways of archiving old chats into something more future proof, but it seems like these tools are very limited. They either don&amp;rsquo;t exist, or only work for specific scenarios like one-on-one chats without attachments.
Today, the situation gets a bit better for one platform, GroupMe. GroupMe is a platform focused on group messaging, and features nice subtle features like likes per message, attachments and so on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep Learning for NLP Crash Course @ Uni Duisburg-Essen</title>
      <link>https://fdalvi.github.io/blog/2018-04-15-dl4nlp-duisburg/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Apr 2018 19:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fdalvi.github.io/blog/2018-04-15-dl4nlp-duisburg/</guid>
      <description>Hassan Sajjad and I just had a great time delivering a 5-day crash course at the Universität Duisburg-Essen. It was delivered roughly over 18 hours - with quite a lot of practical exercises! Check out the course materials.
Duisburg was a nice and calm place, with a döner restaurant ready to greet you almost around every corner. The Königstraße was super-lively with a lot of pop-up shops and restaurants, and was quite a fun walk in the afternoon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One-Hot layer in Keras&#39;s Sequential API</title>
      <link>https://fdalvi.github.io/blog/2018-04-07-keras-sequential-onehot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Apr 2018 20:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fdalvi.github.io/blog/2018-04-07-keras-sequential-onehot/</guid>
      <description>It is quite common to use a One-Hot representation for categorical data in machine learning, for example textual instances in Natural Language Processing tasks. In Keras, the Embedding layer automatically takes inputs with the category indices (such as [5, 3, 1, 5]) and converts them into dense vectors of some length (e.g. 5 → [0.2 1.7 3.2 -7.6 ...]). What actually happens internally is that 5 gets converted to a one-hot vector (like [0 0 0 0 0 1 0 0 .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speech Translation at ALT wins the Best Innovation Award</title>
      <link>https://fdalvi.github.io/blog/2018-03-21-arc-best-innovation-award/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2018 14:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fdalvi.github.io/blog/2018-03-21-arc-best-innovation-award/</guid>
      <description>One of our projects in the Arabic Language Team at the Qatar Computing Research Institute is the Speech Translation Project - a real-time low-latency system where a speaker&amp;rsquo;s voice is transcribed and translated (both in Arabic or English). Check out the project here.
This project was recently awarded the Best Innovation Award at the annual Qatar Foundation Annual Research Conference! It was been a long effort to take our state-of-the-art research in Speech Recognition and Machine Translation and bring it all together in one system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network throttling in Puppeteer</title>
      <link>https://fdalvi.github.io/blog/2018-02-05-puppeteer-network-throttle/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2018 22:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fdalvi.github.io/blog/2018-02-05-puppeteer-network-throttle/</guid>
      <description>Puppeteer is an awesome way to run Chrome (or Chromium) in headless mode, i.e. load and interact with web pages without ever visually seeing them.
Why would this be useful?
A headless browser is a great way to automate testing, even on remote server machines!
Puppeteer provides a nice interface through Node to script any interactions you can have with a page, like entering input in a textbox, clicking a button and so on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>15-213: Introduction to Computer Systems</title>
      <link>https://fdalvi.github.io/teaching/2013-15213-computer-systems-cmuq/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fdalvi.github.io/teaching/2013-15213-computer-systems-cmuq/</guid>
      <description>As a Teaching Assistant for the course, part of my responsibilities was to prepare and deliver recitations every Thursday. These recitations reviewed the material from the week&amp;rsquo;s lectures, talked about assignments and just generally served as a platform to clear any lingering confusion or doubts. All these slides were created from scratch, but a lot of inspiration was drawn from previous recitations for the same course.
Week 1: Introduction [slides] Week 2: Floating point representations [slides] Week 3: Introduction to Assembly [slides] [code] Week 4: Assembly continued [slides] [code] Week 5: C Data-structures [slides] [code] Week 6: System Memory management [slides] Week 7: Exam 1 preparation [slides] Week 8: C Signals and UNIX IO [slides] [code] Week 9: Virtual Memory [slides] [code] Week 10: Memory Allocation in C and Debugging tips [slides] Week 11: Exam 2 preparation [slides] Week 12: Proxies [slides] Week 13: Proxies continued and concurrency [slides] [code] Week 14: Final exam review [slides] Feel free to use the above material for your own courses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep Learning for Machine Translation</title>
      <link>https://fdalvi.github.io/teaching/2017-dgfs-cl/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fdalvi.github.io/teaching/2017-dgfs-cl/</guid>
      <description>Hassan Sajjad and I were fortunate enough to have the opportunity to teach a deep learning course at the Computation Linguistics school organized by Deutsche Gesellschaft für Sprachwissenschaft. This course is geared towards students with a limited background in deep and machine learning. It walks them through building their very first machine learning model, all the way up to developing a strong intuition behind sequence-to-sequence models, with the material wrapped in the context of language.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Theory to Practice: Deep Learning for NLP</title>
      <link>https://fdalvi.github.io/teaching/2018-dl4nlp-duisburg/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fdalvi.github.io/teaching/2018-dl4nlp-duisburg/</guid>
      <description>Hassan Sajjad and I got another chance to teach our deep learning course, but this time it was only for five days, delivered over roughly 18 hours! This course is a bit more general than our DGfS course, and has a lot more practical material.
The official spiel In this lecture series, we cover the basics of machine learning, neural networks and deep neural networks. We look at several deep neural network architectures from the perspective of applying them to various classification tasks, such as sequence prediction and generation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Live Speech Translation</title>
      <link>https://fdalvi.github.io/projects/live-speech-translation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fdalvi.github.io/projects/live-speech-translation/</guid>
      <description>More details coming soon!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
