<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Fahim Dalvi</title>
    <link>https://fdalvi.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Fahim Dalvi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2018 22:00:00 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://fdalvi.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://fdalvi.github.io/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fdalvi.github.io/projects/</guid>
      <description> Live Speech Translation
Bilingual Arabic and English transcription and translation platform with a robust backend enabling live broadcastable sessions
React NodeJS MongoDB Nginx Puppeteer Artillery.io    Machine Translation API
Distributed backend managing multiple machine translation engines built at QCRI and a simple to use user-facing REST API. Served over 400K requests from 30+ countries so far! Python React NodeJS MongoDB Grommet   More to come!   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>https://fdalvi.github.io/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fdalvi.github.io/research/</guid>
      <description>2017   Neural Machine Translation Training in a Multi-Domain Scenario  Hassan Sajjad, Nadir Durrani, Fahim Dalvi, Yonatan Belinkov, Stephan Vogel   International Workshop on Spoken Language Translation 2017 In this paper, we explore alternative ways to train a neural machine translation system in a multi-domain scenario. We investigate data concatenation (with fine tuning), model stacking (multi-level fine tuning), data selection and weighted ensemble. Our findings show that the best translation quality can be achieved by building an initial system on a concatenation of available out-of-domain data and then fine-tuning it on in-domain data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching</title>
      <link>https://fdalvi.github.io/teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fdalvi.github.io/teaching/</guid>
      <description> Minimalism is not a lack of something. It’s simply the perfect amount of something. — Nicholas Burroughs
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network throttling in Puppeteer</title>
      <link>https://fdalvi.github.io/blog/2018-02-05-puppeteer-network-throttle/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2018 22:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fdalvi.github.io/blog/2018-02-05-puppeteer-network-throttle/</guid>
      <description>Puppeteer is an awesome way to run Chrome (or Chromium) in headless mode, i.e. load and interact with web pages without ever visually seeing them.
 Why would this be useful?
A headless browser is a great way to automate testing, even on remote server machines!
 Puppeteer provides a nice interface through Node to script any interactions you can have with a page, like entering input in a textbox, clicking a button and so on.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>