<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>techtips on Fahim Dalvi</title>
    <link>https://fdalvi.github.io/categories/techtips/</link>
    <description>Recent content in techtips on Fahim Dalvi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Jun 2021 12:00:00 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://fdalvi.github.io/categories/techtips/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Consuming Paginated API&#39;s in Javascript</title>
      <link>https://fdalvi.github.io/blog/2021-06-11-consume-paginated-apis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jun 2021 12:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fdalvi.github.io/blog/2021-06-11-consume-paginated-apis/</guid>
      <description>Several providers adopt a notion of pagination in their API&amp;rsquo;s when the number of results from a query is large. This is common to see when the API provides a list of things, like users, billing statements, posts and so on.
A pattern that is adopted by several providers works as follows:
 Developer makes a request to provider (e.g. for the billing statements) The API returns a &amp;ldquo;page&amp;rdquo; with say 10 statements, and a link to the next page Developer makes a request to the provided link The API returns another &amp;ldquo;page&amp;rdquo; with statements, and no link Seeing no link, the developer now knows that all the required entries have been fetched  The number of pages can be dynamic, so the developer needs to keep following the links until they exist if they want to fetch all the results.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating Video Screencaps using FFMPEG and ImageMagick</title>
      <link>https://fdalvi.github.io/blog/2018-09-01-creating-video-screencaps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 12:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fdalvi.github.io/blog/2018-09-01-creating-video-screencaps/</guid>
      <description>I recently wanted to create screencaps for a large set of videos of various lengths and resolutions - basically screenshot each video 5 times, and then combine these 5 screencaps all into one nice image per video, with all of the images being of consistent size.
  Sample render from a seaplane ride over Vancouver
 
 There are a bunch of tools available online that I can either install locally, or upload my video files to get similar results - but given that this was easily achievable using simple tools like ffmpeg and imagemagick, I decided to whip up a quick script to accomplish this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One-Hot layer in Keras&#39;s Sequential API</title>
      <link>https://fdalvi.github.io/blog/2018-04-07-keras-sequential-onehot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Apr 2018 20:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fdalvi.github.io/blog/2018-04-07-keras-sequential-onehot/</guid>
      <description>It is quite common to use a One-Hot representation for categorical data in machine learning, for example textual instances in Natural Language Processing tasks. In Keras, the Embedding layer automatically takes inputs with the category indices (such as [5, 3, 1, 5]) and converts them into dense vectors of some length (e.g. 5 → [0.2 1.7 3.2 -7.6 ...]). What actually happens internally is that 5 gets converted to a one-hot vector (like [0 0 0 0 0 1 0 0 .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network throttling in Puppeteer</title>
      <link>https://fdalvi.github.io/blog/2018-02-05-puppeteer-network-throttle/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2018 22:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fdalvi.github.io/blog/2018-02-05-puppeteer-network-throttle/</guid>
      <description>Puppeteer is an awesome way to run Chrome (or Chromium) in headless mode, i.e. load and interact with web pages without ever visually seeing them.
 Why would this be useful?
A headless browser is a great way to automate testing, even on remote server machines!
 Puppeteer provides a nice interface through Node to script any interactions you can have with a page, like entering input in a textbox, clicking a button and so on.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>