<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>news on Fahim Dalvi</title>
    <link>https://fdalvi.github.io/categories/news/</link>
    <description>Recent content in news on Fahim Dalvi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Apr 2018 19:00:00 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://fdalvi.github.io/categories/news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep Learning for NLP Crash Course @ Uni Duisburg-Essen</title>
      <link>https://fdalvi.github.io/blog/2018-04-15-dl4nlp-duisburg/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Apr 2018 19:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fdalvi.github.io/blog/2018-04-15-dl4nlp-duisburg/</guid>
      <description>Hassan Sajjad and I just had a great time delivering a 5-day crash course at the Universität Duisburg-Essen. It was delivered roughly over 18 hours - with quite a lot of practical exercises! Check out the course materials.
Duisburg was a nice and calm place, with a döner restaurant ready to greet you almost around every corner. The Königstraße was super-lively with a lot of pop-up shops and restaurants, and was quite a fun walk in the afternoon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speech Translation at ALT wins the Best Innovation Award</title>
      <link>https://fdalvi.github.io/blog/2018-03-21-arc-best-innovation-award/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2018 14:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fdalvi.github.io/blog/2018-03-21-arc-best-innovation-award/</guid>
      <description>One of our projects in the Arabic Language Team at the Qatar Computing Research Institute is the Speech Translation Project - a real-time low-latency system where a speaker&amp;rsquo;s voice is transcribed and translated (both in Arabic or English). Check out the project here.
This project was recently awarded the Best Innovation Award at the annual Qatar Foundation Annual Research Conference! It was been a long effort to take our state-of-the-art research in Speech Recognition and Machine Translation and bring it all together in one system.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>