<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pages on Fahim Dalvi</title>
    <link>https://fdalvi.github.io/page/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pages on Fahim Dalvi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    
	<atom:link href="https://fdalvi.github.io/page/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://fdalvi.github.io/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fdalvi.github.io/projects/</guid>
      <description> Live Speech Translation
Bilingual Arabic and English transcription and translation platform with a robust backend enabling live broadcastable sessions
React NodeJS MongoDB Nginx Puppeteer Artillery.io    Machine Translation API
Distributed backend managing multiple machine translation engines built at QCRI and a simple to use user-facing REST API. Served over 400K requests from 30+ countries so far! Python React NodeJS MongoDB Grommet   More to come!   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>https://fdalvi.github.io/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fdalvi.github.io/research/</guid>
      <description>2018 Coming soon!
 2017  Neural Machine Translation Training in a Multi-Domain Scenario  Hassan Sajjad, Nadir Durrani, Fahim Dalvi, Yonatan Belinkov, Stephan Vogel   International Workshop on Spoken Language Translation 2017 In this paper, we explore alternative ways to train a neural machine translation system in a multi-domain scenario. We investigate data concatenation (with fine tuning), model stacking (multi-level fine tuning), data selection and weighted ensemble. Our findings show that the best translation quality can be achieved by building an initial system on a concatenation of available out-of-domain data and then fine-tuning it on in-domain data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching</title>
      <link>https://fdalvi.github.io/teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fdalvi.github.io/teaching/</guid>
      <description>15-213: Introduction to Computer Systems (Recitations) Carnegie Mellon University Qatar, Fall 2013 As a Teaching Assistant for the Introduction to Computer Systems course at CMU-Q, I prepared and delivered recitation sections weekly over the 14-week semester. These materials include the slides, code and illustrations that hopefully make Computer Systems more accessible!   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>15-213: Introduction to Computer Systems</title>
      <link>https://fdalvi.github.io/teaching/2013-15213-computer-systems-cmuq/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fdalvi.github.io/teaching/2013-15213-computer-systems-cmuq/</guid>
      <description>As a Teaching Assistant for the course, part of my responsibilities was to prepare and deliver recitations every Thursday. These recitations reviewed the material from the week&amp;rsquo;s lectures, talked about assignments and just generally served as a platform to clear any lingering confusion or doubts. All these slides were created from scratch, but a lot of inspiration was drawn from previous recitations for the same course.
 Week 1: Introduction [slides] Week 2: Floating point representations [slides] Week 3: Introduction to Assembly [slides] [code] Week 4: Assembly continued [slides] [code] Week 5: C Data-structures [slides] [code] Week 6: System Memory managment [slides] Week 7: Exam 1 preparation [slides] Week 8: C Signals and UNIX IO [slides] [code] Week 9: Virtual Memory [slides] [code] Week 10: Memory Allocation in C and Debugging tips [slides] Week 11: Exam 2 preparation [slides] Week 12: Proxies [slides] Week 13: Proxies continued and concurrency [slides] [code] Week 14: Final exam review [slides]  Feel free to use the above material for your own courses.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>