<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pages on Fahim Dalvi</title>
    <link>https://fdalvi.github.io/page/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pages on Fahim Dalvi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    
	<atom:link href="https://fdalvi.github.io/page/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://fdalvi.github.io/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fdalvi.github.io/projects/</guid>
      <description> Live Speech Translation
Bilingual Arabic and English transcription and translation platform with a robust backend enabling live broadcastable sessions
React NodeJS MongoDB Nginx Puppeteer Artillery.io    Machine Translation API
Distributed backend managing multiple machine translation engines built at QCRI and a simple to use user-facing REST API. Served over 400K requests from 30+ countries so far! Python React NodeJS MongoDB Grommet   More to come!   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>https://fdalvi.github.io/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fdalvi.github.io/research/</guid>
      <description>2021  Fighting the COVID-19 Infodemic: Modeling the Perspective of Journalists, Fact-Checkers, Social Media Platforms, Policy Makers, and the Society  Firoj Alam, Shaden Shaar, Fahim Dalvi, Hassan Sajjad, Alex Nikolov, Hamdy Mubarak, Giovanni Da San Martino, Ahmed Abdelali, Nadir Durrani, Kareem Darwish, Abdulaziz Al-Homaid, Wajdi Zaghouani, Tommaso Caselli, Gijs Danoe, Friso Stolk, Britt Bruntink, Preslav Nakov   Findings of the Association for Computational Linguistics: EMNLP 2021 With the emergence of the COVID-19 pandemic, the political and the medical aspects of disinformation merged as the problem got elevated to a whole new level to become the first global infodemic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching</title>
      <link>https://fdalvi.github.io/teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fdalvi.github.io/teaching/</guid>
      <description>From Theory to Practice: Deep Learning for NLP Co-Lecturer Universität Duisburg-Essen, 2018 A 5-day lecture series covering the basics of machine learning, neural networks and deep neural networks. We look at several deep neural network architectures from the perspective of applying them to various classification tasks, such as sequence prediction and generation. Every lecture is accompanied with practice problems implemented in Keras, a popular Python framework for deep learning.   Deep Learning for Machine Translation Co-Lecturer DGfS Computational Linguistics Fall School, 2017 A 10-lecture crash course in deep learning, specialized towards machine translation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>15-213: Introduction to Computer Systems</title>
      <link>https://fdalvi.github.io/teaching/2013-15213-computer-systems-cmuq/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fdalvi.github.io/teaching/2013-15213-computer-systems-cmuq/</guid>
      <description>As a Teaching Assistant for the course, part of my responsibilities was to prepare and deliver recitations every Thursday. These recitations reviewed the material from the week&amp;rsquo;s lectures, talked about assignments and just generally served as a platform to clear any lingering confusion or doubts. All these slides were created from scratch, but a lot of inspiration was drawn from previous recitations for the same course.
 Week 1: Introduction [slides] Week 2: Floating point representations [slides] Week 3: Introduction to Assembly [slides] [code] Week 4: Assembly continued [slides] [code] Week 5: C Data-structures [slides] [code] Week 6: System Memory management [slides] Week 7: Exam 1 preparation [slides] Week 8: C Signals and UNIX IO [slides] [code] Week 9: Virtual Memory [slides] [code] Week 10: Memory Allocation in C and Debugging tips [slides] Week 11: Exam 2 preparation [slides] Week 12: Proxies [slides] Week 13: Proxies continued and concurrency [slides] [code] Week 14: Final exam review [slides]  Feel free to use the above material for your own courses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep Learning for Machine Translation</title>
      <link>https://fdalvi.github.io/teaching/2017-dgfs-cl/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fdalvi.github.io/teaching/2017-dgfs-cl/</guid>
      <description>Hassan Sajjad and I were fortunate enough to have the opportunity to teach a deep learning course at the Computation Linguistics school organized by Deutsche Gesellschaft für Sprachwissenschaft. This course is geared towards students with a limited background in deep and machine learning. It walks them through building their very first machine learning model, all the way up to developing a strong intuition behind sequence-to-sequence models, with the material wrapped in the context of language.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Theory to Practice: Deep Learning for NLP</title>
      <link>https://fdalvi.github.io/teaching/2018-dl4nlp-duisburg/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fdalvi.github.io/teaching/2018-dl4nlp-duisburg/</guid>
      <description>Hassan Sajjad and I got another chance to teach our deep learning course, but this time it was only for five days, delivered over roughly 18 hours! This course is a bit more general than our DGfS course, and has a lot more practical material.
The official spiel  In this lecture series, we cover the basics of machine learning, neural networks and deep neural networks. We look at several deep neural network architectures from the perspective of applying them to various classification tasks, such as sequence prediction and generation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Live Speech Translation</title>
      <link>https://fdalvi.github.io/projects/live-speech-translation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fdalvi.github.io/projects/live-speech-translation/</guid>
      <description>More details coming soon!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>